Jeremiah Boyle

Software Engineer

jeremiah.boyle@gmail.com (415) 205-9443

SKILLS

Backend swiss-army knife favoring Python and C# but comfortable in C++, Java, Ruby, and JavaScript. Accustomed to agile methods, domain-driven design, and test-driven development. Experienced with both containerized and serverless strategies supported by Amazon Web Services, PostgreSQL, Docker, AMQP.

EXPERIENCE

Principal Software Engineer

iBeat

June 2018 - Present San Francisco. CA

Designed and implemented over-the-air firmware update infrastructure for consumer wearable. Devised version system, messaging protocol, and algorithm capable of coping with unreliable communication channel.

Donned DevOps hat to straighten up existing Lambda-based microservices backend with continuous testing and deployment, infrastructure-as-code, monitoring, and error reporting.

Lead Software Engineer

Kalo

2016 - 2018

San Francisco, CA

Modeled and led team which built and supported Kalo Pay payment processing system which produced the bulk of company's revenue. Integrated several third-party payment processors to piece together global international support.

Deleted 12% of codebase in a week by extricating email notification logic from business logic and into an event-driven microservice, reducing developer pain and increasing productivity.

Created take-home assignment for engineering applicants and conducted pair-programming interviews with candidates.

Senior Software Engineer

2008 - 2016

Roon Labs (f.k.a Meridian Audio, Sooloos)

San Francisco, CA

Created world's most extensive music metadata database by leveraging parallell processing to retrieve, normalize, analyze, and cross-reference all leading music data sources. Designed identification service capable of turning a mislabeled Napster mp3 into a portfolio of metadata and relationships (images, artist biography, local tour dates, etc).

Simultaneously built and supported Mac, Windows, iOS, and Android native application ports by quickly prototyping a web-based UI (later replaced with performant GL) to maximally leverage code sharing.

Resolved circular dependency between iOS and field hardware with a protocol negotiation service and discreetly loaded interpreted code on iOS. Exposed Obj-C messaging to embedded script engine and built UIKit bindings by hand.

Software Engineer

2006 - 2008

Bloomberg L.P.

New York, NY

Freed 1,200 developers from dependence on legacy (FORTRAN, circa 1982) date/currency string utility by reverse-engineering original FORTRAN, designing a format grammar, and implementing an extensible plug-in architecture in C++.

EDUCATION

B.S. Computer Engineering with Highest Honor

2004 Atlanta, GA